{"settings":{"volume":50,"voiceType":"english","speed":62},"allCompletedGame":false,"gameQuestions":[{"correctlyAnswered":false,"question":"This New Zealander had a worldwide hit with the song \u2018Royal\u201D","answers":["Lorde"],"completed":false,"category":"Famous People","worth":1100},{"correctlyAnswered":false,"question":"This is what Dame Kiri Te Kanawa was famous for","answers":["Opera Singing"],"completed":false,"category":"Famous People","worth":900},{"correctlyAnswered":false,"question":"The New Zealander directed \u201CThe Lord of the Rings\u201D and \u201CThe Hobbit\u201D","answers":["Peter Jackson"],"completed":false,"category":"Famous People","worth":700},{"correctlyAnswered":false,"question":"This New Zealander was the first person to climb mount Everest","answers":["Edmund Hillary"],"completed":false,"category":"Famous People","worth":500},{"correctlyAnswered":false,"question":"This New Zealander directed \u201CJojo Rabbit\u201D and \u201CThor: Ragnarok\u201D","answers":["Taika Waititi"],"completed":false,"category":"Famous People","worth":800},{"correctlyAnswered":false,"question":"This animal is known as Kiore in Māori","answers":["black rat"],"completed":false,"category":"Fauna","worth":600},{"correctlyAnswered":false,"question":"This large brown flightless bird is known for being curious and a bit of a thief","answers":["Weka"],"completed":false,"category":"Fauna","worth":800},{"correctlyAnswered":false,"question":"This common forest bird is known for its beautiful song, and distinctive white tuft under their throat","answers":["Tui"],"completed":false,"category":"Fauna","worth":1100},{"correctlyAnswered":false,"question":"This is called a living dinosaur","answers":["Tuatara"],"completed":false,"category":"Fauna","worth":600},{"correctlyAnswered":false,"question":"This is the common name for the New Zealand owl","answers":["Morepork"],"completed":false,"category":"Fauna","worth":700},{"correctlyAnswered":false,"question":"This is the name of the sea between New Zealand and Australia","answers":["Tasman"],"completed":false,"category":"Geography","worth":900},{"correctlyAnswered":false,"question":"This is the name of the sea between the North and the South Island","answers":["Cook Strait"],"completed":false,"category":"Geography","worth":1000},{"correctlyAnswered":false,"question":"This is the largest active volcano in New Zealand","answers":["Ruaphehu"],"completed":false,"category":"Geography","worth":1400},{"correctlyAnswered":false,"question":"This is the highest mountain in New Zealand","answers":["Mt Cook"],"completed":false,"category":"Geography","worth":600},{"correctlyAnswered":false,"question":"This is the name of the ocean New Zealand sits in","answers":["Pacific"],"completed":false,"category":"Geography","worth":800},{"correctlyAnswered":false,"question":"This city is nicknamed the Edinburgh of the South","answers":["Dunedin"],"completed":false,"category":"Places","worth":1500},{"correctlyAnswered":false,"question":"This is the city that is the first to see the sunrise each day","answers":["Gisborne"],"completed":false,"category":"Places","worth":1200},{"correctlyAnswered":false,"question":"This is the most southern port in the South Island","answers":["Bluff"],"completed":false,"category":"Places","worth":1400},{"correctlyAnswered":false,"question":"This is the Māori name for New Zealand","answers":["Aotearoa"],"completed":false,"category":"Places","worth":600},{"correctlyAnswered":false,"question":"This is the most northern tip on the North Island","answers":["Cape Reinga"],"completed":false,"category":"Places","worth":1300},{"correctlyAnswered":false,"question":"The New Zealand term for swimwear","answers":["Togs"],"completed":false,"category":"NZ Life","worth":900},{"correctlyAnswered":false,"question":"This is the Māori word for sweet potato","answers":["Kumara"],"completed":false,"category":"NZ Life","worth":700},{"correctlyAnswered":false,"question":"This is the name of the underground method of cooking used in New Zealand","answers":["hangi"],"completed":false,"category":"NZ Life","worth":800},{"correctlyAnswered":false,"question":"This is the Māori word for stomach","answers":["Puku"],"completed":false,"category":"NZ Life","worth":600},{"correctlyAnswered":false,"question":"This is the name for a traditional fenced Māori village","answers":["Pā"],"completed":false,"category":"NZ Life","worth":500}],"currentCategory":"Places","questions":[{"correctlyAnswered":false,"question":"This is the capital of New Zealand","answers":["Wellington"],"completed":false,"category":"Places","worth":500},{"correctlyAnswered":false,"question":"This is the Māori name for New Zealand","answers":["Aotearoa"],"completed":false,"category":"Places","worth":600},{"correctlyAnswered":false,"question":"This is the largest city in New Zealand","answers":["Auckland"],"completed":false,"category":"Places","worth":700},{"correctlyAnswered":false,"question":"This is the name of the port that serves Christchurch","answers":["Lyttleton"],"completed":false,"category":"Places","worth":800},{"correctlyAnswered":false,"question":"This is the name of the Parliament Building in Wellington","answers":["Beehive"],"completed":false,"category":"Places","worth":900},{"correctlyAnswered":false,"question":"This is the name of New Zealand\u2019s national museum","answers":["Te Papa"],"completed":false,"category":"Places","worth":1000},{"correctlyAnswered":false,"question":"This is the island in New Zealand that has the largest population","answers":["North Island"],"completed":false,"category":"Places","worth":1100},{"correctlyAnswered":false,"question":"This is the city that is the first to see the sunrise each day","answers":["Gisborne"],"completed":false,"category":"Places","worth":1200},{"correctlyAnswered":false,"question":"This is the most northern tip on the North Island","answers":["Cape Reinga"],"completed":false,"category":"Places","worth":1300},{"correctlyAnswered":false,"question":"This is the most southern port in the South Island","answers":["Bluff"],"completed":false,"category":"Places","worth":1400},{"correctlyAnswered":false,"question":"This city is nicknamed the Edinburgh of the South","answers":["Dunedin"],"completed":false,"category":"Places","worth":1500},{"correctlyAnswered":false,"question":"The number of river systems that flow through either the North or South Island","answers":["70"],"completed":false,"category":"Places","worth":1600},{"correctlyAnswered":false,"question":"These are the colours on the New Zealand Flag","answers":["Red, White, Blue"],"completed":false,"category":"Symbols","worth":500},{"correctlyAnswered":false,"question":"This is the number of stars on the New Zealand flag","answers":["four"],"completed":false,"category":"Symbols","worth":600},{"correctlyAnswered":false,"question":"This is the ship on the 50 cent coin","answers":["Endeavour"],"completed":false,"category":"Symbols","worth":700},{"correctlyAnswered":true,"question":"This plant is the national symbol of New Zealand","answers":["Silver fern"],"completed":false,"category":"Symbols","worth":800},{"correctlyAnswered":false,"question":"These are the birds that New Zealanders are named after","answers":["Kiwi"],"completed":false,"category":"Symbols","worth":900},{"correctlyAnswered":false,"question":"This is the flightless bird that features in the Royal New Zealand Airforce logo","answers":["Kiwi"],"completed":false,"category":"Symbols","worth":1000},{"correctlyAnswered":false,"question":"This is what the stars on the New Zealand flag represent","answers":["Southern Cross"],"completed":false,"category":"Symbols","worth":1100},{"correctlyAnswered":false,"question":"This is the largest lake in New Zealand","answers":["Taupo"],"completed":false,"category":"Geography","worth":500},{"correctlyAnswered":false,"question":"This is the highest mountain in New Zealand","answers":["Mt Cook"],"completed":false,"category":"Geography","worth":600},{"correctlyAnswered":false,"question":"This is the longest river in New Zealand","answers":["Waikato"],"completed":false,"category":"Geography","worth":700},{"correctlyAnswered":false,"question":"This is the name of the ocean New Zealand sits in","answers":["Pacific"],"completed":false,"category":"Geography","worth":800},{"correctlyAnswered":false,"question":"This is the name of the sea between New Zealand and Australia","answers":["Tasman"],"completed":false,"category":"Geography","worth":900},{"correctlyAnswered":false,"question":"This is the name of the sea between the North and the South Island","answers":["Cook Strait"],"completed":false,"category":"Geography","worth":1000},{"correctlyAnswered":false,"question":"This is the name of the long chain of mountains that make up the backbone of the South Island","answers":["Southern Alps"],"completed":false,"category":"Geography","worth":1100},{"correctlyAnswered":false,"question":"This volcano in Auckland last erupted 20,000 years ago, and was the site of a major pā","answers":["Mount Māngere"],"completed":false,"category":"Geography","worth":1200},{"correctlyAnswered":false,"question":"This volcano emerged unexpectedly in the Hauraki gulf about 600 years ago","answers":["Rangitoto"],"completed":false,"category":"Geography","worth":1300},{"correctlyAnswered":false,"question":"This is the largest active volcano in New Zealand","answers":["Ruaphehu"],"completed":false,"category":"Geography","worth":1400},{"correctlyAnswered":false,"question":"This is the third largest island of New Zealand","answers":["Stewart Island"],"completed":false,"category":"Geography","worth":1500},{"correctlyAnswered":false,"question":"This is the name of the ship Captain Cook sailed on to New Zealand","answers":["Endeavour"],"completed":false,"category":"History","worth":500},{"correctlyAnswered":false,"question":"This is the year the treaty of Waitangi was signed","answers":["1840"],"completed":false,"category":"History","worth":600},{"correctlyAnswered":false,"question":"This is the year women first got to vote in New Zealand","answers":["1893"],"completed":false,"category":"History","worth":700},{"correctlyAnswered":false,"question":"This is the first country in the world to give women the vote","answers":["New Zealand"],"completed":false,"category":"History","worth":800},{"correctlyAnswered":false,"question":"This is the first person to step foot on New Zealand","answers":["Kupe"],"completed":false,"category":"History","worth":900},{"correctlyAnswered":false,"question":"This city was the capital of New Zealand before it moved in Wellington","answers":["Auckland"],"completed":false,"category":"History","worth":1000},{"correctlyAnswered":false,"question":"The eruption from this volcano happened in 1886 and destroyed several villages","answers":["Mount Tarawera"],"completed":false,"category":"History","worth":1100},{"correctlyAnswered":false,"question":"On the 22 February 2011, a magnitude 6.3 earthquake hit this city","answers":["Christchurch"],"completed":false,"category":"History","worth":1200},{"correctlyAnswered":false,"question":"This New Zealander was the first person to climb mount Everest","answers":["Edmund Hillary"],"completed":false,"category":"Famous People","worth":500},{"correctlyAnswered":false,"question":"This New Zealander was the first person to split the atom","answers":["Ernest Rutherford"],"completed":false,"category":"Famous People","worth":600},{"correctlyAnswered":false,"question":"The New Zealander directed \u201CThe Lord of the Rings\u201D and \u201CThe Hobbit\u201D","answers":["Peter Jackson"],"completed":false,"category":"Famous People","worth":700},{"correctlyAnswered":false,"question":"This New Zealander directed \u201CJojo Rabbit\u201D and \u201CThor: Ragnarok\u201D","answers":["Taika Waititi"],"completed":false,"category":"Famous People","worth":800},{"correctlyAnswered":false,"question":"This is what Dame Kiri Te Kanawa was famous for","answers":["Opera Singing"],"completed":false,"category":"Famous People","worth":900},{"correctlyAnswered":false,"question":"This New Zealander sung at the wedding of Prince Charles and Lady Diana","answers":["Kiri Te Kanawa"],"completed":false,"category":"Famous People","worth":1000},{"correctlyAnswered":false,"question":"This New Zealander had a worldwide hit with the song \u2018Royal\u201D","answers":["Lorde"],"completed":false,"category":"Famous People","worth":1100},{"correctlyAnswered":false,"question":"This New Zealander led the 1975 land march from Te Hapua to Parliament","answers":["Dame Whina Cooper"],"completed":false,"category":"Famous People","worth":1200},{"correctlyAnswered":false,"question":"This is the name for a traditional fenced Māori village","answers":["Pā"],"completed":false,"category":"NZ Life","worth":500},{"correctlyAnswered":false,"question":"This is the Māori word for stomach","answers":["Puku"],"completed":false,"category":"NZ Life","worth":600},{"correctlyAnswered":false,"question":"This is the Māori word for sweet potato","answers":["Kumara"],"completed":false,"category":"NZ Life","worth":700},{"correctlyAnswered":false,"question":"This is the name of the underground method of cooking used in New Zealand","answers":["hangi"],"completed":false,"category":"NZ Life","worth":800},{"correctlyAnswered":false,"question":"The New Zealand term for swimwear","answers":["Togs"],"completed":false,"category":"NZ Life","worth":900},{"correctlyAnswered":false,"question":"These shoes are called flip flops or thongs in other countries","answers":["Jandals"],"completed":false,"category":"NZ Life","worth":1000},{"correctlyAnswered":false,"question":"This is the largest native tree in New Zealand","answers":["Kauri"],"completed":false,"category":"Flora","worth":500},{"correctlyAnswered":false,"question":"This well known fruit use to be called the Chinese Gooseberry","answers":["Kiwifruit"],"completed":false,"category":"Flora","worth":600},{"correctlyAnswered":false,"question":"New Zealand has 200 of this species, and one species is our national symbol","answers":["fern"],"completed":false,"category":"Flora","worth":700},{"correctlyAnswered":false,"question":"The honey from this plant is known for its medicinal benefits","answers":["Mānuka"],"completed":false,"category":"Flora","worth":800},{"correctlyAnswered":false,"question":"The nectar from bright yellow flowers of this tree are an important food source for native birds","answers":["Kowhai"],"completed":false,"category":"Flora","worth":900},{"correctlyAnswered":false,"question":"This is known as the New Zealand Christmas tree","answers":["Pōhutukawa"],"completed":false,"category":"Flora","worth":1000},{"correctlyAnswered":false,"question":"This green vegetable is a traditional staple food of the Māori","answers":["Pūhā"],"completed":false,"category":"Flora","worth":1100},{"correctlyAnswered":false,"question":"This is the plant that the Māori weaved into baskets","answers":["Flax"],"completed":false,"category":"Flora","worth":1200},{"correctlyAnswered":false,"question":"This introduced alga is a threat to New Zealand rivers and is known as rock snot","answers":["Didymo"],"completed":false,"category":"Flora","worth":1300},{"correctlyAnswered":false,"question":"This is New Zealand\u2019s mountain parrot","answers":["Kea"],"completed":false,"category":"Fauna","worth":500},{"correctlyAnswered":false,"question":"This is called a living dinosaur","answers":["Tuatara"],"completed":false,"category":"Fauna","worth":600},{"correctlyAnswered":false,"question":"This is the common name for the New Zealand owl","answers":["Morepork"],"completed":false,"category":"Fauna","worth":700},{"correctlyAnswered":false,"question":"This native bird lays the largest egg in relation to their body size of any species of bird in the world","answers":["Kiwi"],"completed":false,"category":"Fauna","worth":800},{"correctlyAnswered":false,"question":"This is the now extinct giant flightless bird that inhabited all of New Zealand","answers":["Moa"],"completed":false,"category":"Fauna","worth":900},{"correctlyAnswered":false,"question":"This is the only land mammal native to New Zealand","answers":["bat"],"completed":false,"category":"Fauna","worth":1000},{"correctlyAnswered":false,"question":"This is the number of Kiwi species","answers":["five"],"completed":false,"category":"Fauna","worth":1100},{"correctlyAnswered":false,"question":"This is the animal that is the greatest threat to Kiwi","answers":["stoats"],"completed":false,"category":"Fauna","worth":1200},{"correctlyAnswered":false,"question":"This animal was introduced in the late 1700s to New Zealand and can damage the forest ecosystem","answers":["Pigs"],"completed":false,"category":"Fauna","worth":500},{"correctlyAnswered":false,"question":"This animal is known as Kiore in Māori","answers":["black rat"],"completed":false,"category":"Fauna","worth":600},{"correctlyAnswered":false,"question":"This native bird of prey can fly over 1000 kilometers an hour","answers":["New Zealand Falcon"],"completed":false,"category":"Fauna","worth":700},{"correctlyAnswered":false,"question":"This large brown flightless bird is known for being curious and a bit of a thief","answers":["Weka"],"completed":false,"category":"Fauna","worth":800},{"correctlyAnswered":false,"question":"This small common bird has a tail that opens up to look like a fan","answers":["Fantail"],"completed":false,"category":"Fauna","worth":900},{"correctlyAnswered":false,"question":"This large flightless nocturnal parrot is one of New Zealand's most endangered birds","answers":["Kākāpō"],"completed":false,"category":"Fauna","worth":1000},{"correctlyAnswered":false,"question":"This common forest bird is known for its beautiful song, and distinctive white tuft under their throat","answers":["Tui"],"completed":false,"category":"Fauna","worth":1100},{"correctlyAnswered":false,"question":"This is the only poisonous Native spider in New Zealand","answers":["Katipō"],"completed":false,"category":"Fauna","worth":1200},{"correctlyAnswered":false,"question":"This grub chews up wood, and is edible","answers":["Huhu Grub"],"completed":false,"category":"Fauna","worth":1300},{"correctlyAnswered":false,"question":"What is the year the Government pledged New Zealand would be predator free","answers":["2050"],"completed":false,"category":"Oddities","worth":500},{"correctlyAnswered":false,"question":"This is the name of New Zealand Male Rugby Team","answers":["All Blacks"],"completed":false,"category":"Oddities","worth":600},{"correctlyAnswered":false,"question":"What New Zealand song has made it into the New Zealand Top 40 in three separate decades","answers":["Poi E"],"completed":false,"category":"Oddities","worth":700},{"correctlyAnswered":false,"question":"This is the nationality of the inventors of the bobby pin, wide toothed shearing comb, and jet boat","answers":["New Zealander"],"completed":false,"category":"Oddities","worth":800},{"correctlyAnswered":false,"question":"In 1990 New Zealand became the first country in the modern world to make this appointment","answers":["Official National Wizard"],"completed":false,"category":"Oddities","worth":900}],"practiceWinnings":0,"allCompletedPractice":false,"addedToLeaderboard":false,"leaderboard":[{"score":900,"name":"Andreas"}],"name":"Andreas","gameWinnings":0,"categories":["Places","Symbols","Geography","History","Famous People","NZ Life","Flora","Fauna","Oddities"],"currentGameType":"GAMESMODULE","practiceQuestions":[]}